<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on R-Ladies Sydney</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on R-Ladies Sydney</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Basics Lesson 1: RStudio</title>
      <link>/post/2018/11/05/basicbasics-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/11/05/basicbasics-1/</guid>
      <description>Basic Basics Lesson 1: An Opinionated Tour of RStudioHere at R-Ladies Sydney, we’re a pretty opinionated bunch. In this lesson, we’re going to impart our opinions1 on navigating RStudio and setting up your workflow. This forms the foundation of all future RYouWithMe lessons - so be sure to follow along carefully!
Lesson OutcomesBy the end of the lesson, you should:
1.1. Have R and RStudio installed on your machine1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Basics Lesson 2: Packages</title>
      <link>/post/2018/11/05/basicbasics-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/11/05/basicbasics-2/</guid>
      <description>Basic Basics Lesson 2: Installing and Loading PackagesYou likely won’t get very far in R without packages. Sure, you could write all the functions you need for your analysis yourself if you wanted, but the great thing about the #rstats community is that people write code, bundle it into packages, and then give them away FOR FREE. Once you are an #rstats expert, you can create your own packages and give back, but for now lets learn what packages are and how to use them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Basics Lesson 3: Loading Data</title>
      <link>/post/2018/11/05/basicbasics-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/11/05/basicbasics-3/</guid>
      <description>Basic Basics Lesson 3: Loading DataIn this lesson, we’re going to review how to get data into RStudio, using a specially selected data file that we’ll continue to use for many of the RYouWithMe lessons.
Lesson OutcomesBy the end of the lesson, you should:
3.1 Have the sydneybeaches.csv data file saved to your RYouWithMe data folder3.2 Know how to use the here package to tell R where your data is, how to use read_csv to read data from a .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Basics Overview</title>
      <link>/post/2018/11/05/basicbasics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/11/05/basicbasics/</guid>
      <description>RYouWithMe Unit 1 - Basic BasicsIn Unit 1, you’ll lay down the foundational knowledge and skills that will carry you through your R journey!
Unit 1 has three lessons:
An opinionated tour of RStudioInstalling and Loading PackagesGetting data into RStudioAs you embark on Basic Basics, we think this is a useful reminder for R users new and experienced (h/t realpython):
Learning R is a journey - we’re delighted to have you along!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RYouWithMe</title>
      <link>/post/2018/11/01/ryouwithme/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/11/01/ryouwithme/</guid>
      <description>RYouWithMe: The inspirationI’m Lisa Williams, a social psychologist at UNSW Sydney, and co-founder of R-Ladies Sydney. Truth be told, I’m a complete R newbie. Sure, I’ve executed a few commands here and there. But I’ve found R daunting: the workflow, the pure number of packages, and the ‘cross-your-fingers-and-hope’ nature of executing a command. Yet, increasingly, R is the answer to many of my problems - from data wrangling to visualisation to analysis, the result of my searches for how to achieve something is: “you can do it in R”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidyverse for Beginners</title>
      <link>/post/2018/08/21/little-miss-tidyverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/08/21/little-miss-tidyverse/</guid>
      <description>Workshop planAre you new to this R business and short on time? Would you like to start working with data in R without having to go through the arduous process of learning all the programming details first? Do you have a neat data set you’d like to explore and visualise? This might be the workshop for you! Or are you an experienced old school R programmer who learned how to do everything in base R?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launch Event: Lightning Talks</title>
      <link>/post/2018/06/13/lightning-talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/06/13/lightning-talks/</guid>
      <description>We are super excited to announce that R-Ladies Sydney will launch on June 20th 2018 🎉. For our first event, we want everyone to meet someone new and learn something new so we plan to host a series of lightning talks ⚡. You are all invited to come along! We have an awesome lineup of speakers, listed below, so come along and join in!

Jessica LeeTitle: Why I R?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R-Ladies Sydney</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>About the Sydney R-Ladies group R-Ladies Sydney is part of a world-wide organization to promote gender diversity in the R community, with Australian chapters in Melbourne, Adelaide and Brisbane.
The plot to set up a Sydney chapter was hatched by Jenny Richmond , with Danielle Navarro , Lisa Williams  and Steph de Silva  as co-conspirators, and (for the moment at least!) the four of us make up the very friendly leadership group for the chapter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R-Ladies Sydney events</title>
      <link>/events/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/</guid>
      <description>Check out some of the events we’ve hosted! You can find and sign up to new events on our Meetup page.
Machine Learning 101, Part 2, (17-Oct-2018)Presenter: Sarah Romanes (@sarah_romanes)Slides: https://sarahromanes.github.io/r-ladies-ML-2/#1Github: https://github.com/sarahromanes/r-ladies-ML-2Machine Learning 101, Part 1 (10-Oct-2018)Presenter: Sarah Romanes (@sarah_romanes)Slides: https://sarahromanes.github.io/r-ladies-ML-1/#1Github: https://github.com/sarahromanes/r-ladies-ML-1Shiny September: Making an interactive web app in R (19-Sep-2018)Presenter: Emi Tanaka (@statsgen)Slides: https://emitanaka.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>