<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on R-Ladies Sydney</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on R-Ladies Sydney</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>VizW(h)iz 1: Plotting Raw Data</title>
      <link>/post/2018/12/20/vizwhiz-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/12/20/vizwhiz-1/</guid>
      <description>Before we begin, a preamble…
Why plot raw data?Until I1 started learning R about a year ago, I had only ever plotted averaged data. My plots looked like this…
Or this….
In 2016, I remember seeing #barbarplots t-shirts and tote bags at a conference, but back then I didn’t know that the figures were made in R.
Check out this video for more info about the #barbarplots kickstarter campaign.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VizW(h)iz 2: Boxes, Violins, and Histograms</title>
      <link>/post/2018/12/20/vizwhiz-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/12/20/vizwhiz-2/</guid>
      <description>When you want to capture the distribution of your data in a plot, without getting too far away from the raw data, box and whisker plots, violin plots, and histograms are likely to be useful. In this lesson, we’re tackling how to creat these plots using various geom commands!
Lesson OutcomesBy the end of the lesson, you should:
2.1 Be able to use geom_boxplot and geom_violin to plot the distribution of raw data2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VizW(h)iz 3: Bars, Columns, and Scatterplots</title>
      <link>/post/2018/12/20/vizwhiz-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/12/20/vizwhiz-3/</guid>
      <description>The ggplot fanciness we covered in Lesson 1 and Lesson 2 is great, but sometimes your boss/grant agency/publication outlet insists on a bar or column graph. Or perhaps you simply need to visualise two continuous variables. In this lesson, we will show you how to plot bar and column graphs with error bars and how to plot a scatter plot.
Lesson OutcomesBy the end of the lesson, you should:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VizW(h)iz 4: Customising Plots</title>
      <link>/post/2018/12/20/vizwhiz-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/12/20/vizwhiz-4/</guid>
      <description>I google for #rstats code all the time! https://t.co/XDzuvqkJCK— Hadley Wickham (@hadleywickham) July 26, 2016Everyone (even Hadley Wickham!) googles how to make their ggplot look like how they want, every…. single…. time. In this lesson, we are going to show you how to use themes, colours, and labels to get most of the way there.
Lesson OutcomesBy the end of the lesson, you should:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VizW(h)iz 5: GIFS! A VizW(h)iz Bonus Lesson</title>
      <link>/post/2018/12/20/vizwhiz-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/12/20/vizwhiz-5/</guid>
      <description>This bonus VizW(h)iz lesson is a shout-out to R-Ladies Sydney cofounder Lisa Williams. Back in May, she tweeted:
I vote for this as a tutorial at an upcoming @RLadiesSydney meetup! @djnavarro @JenRichmondPhD @StephdeSilva! https://t.co/bBQ4HmbCYW— Dr Lisa A. Williams (@williamslisaphd) May 16, 2018Your wish is our command, Lisa! [pun intended!]
I could not possibly love this more! pic.twitter.com/lQyQlRNVZl— Dr Lisa A. Williams (@williamslisaphd) December 18, 2018--We are quite certain that you’d appreciate knowing how to perform this whizzy wizardry, so here you are: a step-by-step guide to adding a gif to a ggplot!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VizW(h)iz Overview</title>
      <link>/post/2018/12/20/vizwhiz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/12/20/vizwhiz/</guid>
      <description>RYouWithMe Unit 3 - VizW(h)izWelcome to the third unit of RYouWithMe! In Unit 3, we’re tackling data visualisation!
Unit 3 has five lessons:
Plotting Raw DataBoxes, Violins, and HistogramsBars, Columns, and ScatterplotsCustomising PlotsGIFS! A VizW(h)iz Bonus LessonWhy “VizW(h)iz”?R-Ladies Sydney co-founders Lisa Williams and Jen Richmond, who conjured up the name of this unit, had different things in mind! Lisa had in mind “VizWiz” - as in Visualisation Wizardry!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean It Up 4: Wide to Long to Wide to...</title>
      <link>/post/2018/11/28/clean-it-up-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/11/28/clean-it-up-4/</guid>
      <description>Learning how to use gather and spread functions might be one of the biggest stumbling blocks that R learners encounter. Even Rlady ed experts like Jesse Mostipak freely admit to not really “getting it”.
there&#39;s a pretty large discrepancy between how well I think I know spread() and gather() and how well I actually know spread() and gather()— Jesse Mostipak (@kierisi) October 28, 2018Why do you need to know gather and spread?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean It Up 1: Cleaning Up Columns</title>
      <link>/post/2018/11/20/clean-it-up-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/11/20/clean-it-up-1/</guid>
      <description>Which beach is dirtiest? Which council does the best job of preventing beach contamination? Have beaches been getting cleaner in the past 5 years? We can answer all of your questions about the Sydney Beaches dataset, but first we need to do some tidying up.
In this lesson, we’re going to try out the janitor package and use functions from dplyr, a package in the tidyverse that is designed for data wrangling to rename and select columns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean It Up 2: Exploring Rows</title>
      <link>/post/2018/11/20/clean-it-up-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/11/20/clean-it-up-2/</guid>
      <description>Now that we have cleaned up our column names to make them easier to work with, we can start to answer some questions about what’s in those rows! In this lesson, we’re going to filter, arrange, group_by and summarise the beaches data to answer the following questions:
Question A: Which beach has the highest recorded bacteria levels?Question B: Does Coogee or Bondi have more extreme bacteria levels? Which beach has the worst bacteria levels on average?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean It Up 3: Making New Variables</title>
      <link>/post/2018/11/20/clean-it-up-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/11/20/clean-it-up-3/</guid>
      <description>What if the data you are really interested in isn’t in your dataframe yet? Perhaps you want to break data contained in one variable across many variables, or to combine data from several columns into one. Maybe you want to transform your data or compute difference scores.
In this lesson, we will continue to explore the sydneybeaches data, learning how to make new variables in using separate, unite, mutate and other functions from dpylr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean It Up Overview</title>
      <link>/post/2018/11/19/clean-it-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/11/19/clean-it-up/</guid>
      <description>RYouWithMe Unit 2 - Clean It UpWelcome to the second unit of RYouWithMe! In Unit 2, we’re moving on to data cleaning! Trust us, it’s more fun than housecleaning!
Unit 2 has four lessons:
Cleaning Up ColumnsExploring the RowsMaking New VariablesWide to Long to Wide to…via GIPHY</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Basics 1: An Opinionated Tour of RStudio</title>
      <link>/post/2018/11/05/basicbasics-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/11/05/basicbasics-1/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the first lesson of Basic Basics! Here at R-Ladies Sydney, we’re a pretty opinionated bunch. In this lesson, we’re going to impart our opinions1 on navigating RStudio and setting up your workflow. This forms the foundation of all future RYouWithMe lessons - so be sure to follow along carefully!
Lesson OutcomesBy the end of the lesson, you should:
1.1. Have R and RStudio installed on your machine1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Basics 2: Installing and Loading Packages</title>
      <link>/post/2018/11/05/basicbasics-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/11/05/basicbasics-2/</guid>
      <description>For the second lesson in Basic Basics we’re going to talk about packages. You likely won’t get very far in R without packages. Sure, you could write all the functions you need for your analysis yourself if you wanted, but the great thing about the #rstats community is that people write code, bundle it into packages, and then give them away FOR FREE because they are so terribly nice. Once you are an #rstats expert, you can create your own packages and give back, but for now let’s learn what packages are and how to use them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Basics 3: Loading Data</title>
      <link>/post/2018/11/05/basicbasics-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/11/05/basicbasics-3/</guid>
      <description>In this, the third lesson to Basic Basics, we’re going to review how to get data into RStudio, using a specially selected data file that we’ll continue to use for many of the RYouWithMe lessons.
Lesson OutcomesBy the end of the lesson, you should:
3.1 Have the sydneybeaches.csv data file saved to your RYouWithMe data folder3.2 Know how to use the here package to tell R where your data is, how to use read_csv to read data from a .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Basics Overview</title>
      <link>/post/2018/11/05/basicbasics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/11/05/basicbasics/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the first unit of RYouWithMe! In this first unit, you’ll lay down the foundational knowledge and skills that will carry you through your R journey! Since it covers the basics of R in hopefully-straightforward way, we’re calling it Basic Basics…
This unit has three lessons:
An opinionated tour of RStudioInstalling and loading packagesGetting data into RStudioClick on any of the links above to see the lessons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RYouWithMe</title>
      <link>/post/2018/11/01/ryouwithme/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/11/01/ryouwithme/</guid>
      <description>RYouWithMe: The inspirationI’m Lisa Williams, a social psychologist at UNSW Sydney, and co-founder of R-Ladies Sydney. Truth be told, I’m a complete R newbie. Sure, I’ve executed a few commands here and there. But I’ve found R daunting: the workflow, the pure number of packages, and the ‘cross-your-fingers-and-hope’ nature of executing a command. Yet, increasingly, R is the answer to many of my problems - from data wrangling to visualisation to analysis, the result of my searches for how to achieve something is: “you can do it in R”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidyverse for Beginners</title>
      <link>/post/2018/08/21/little-miss-tidyverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/08/21/little-miss-tidyverse/</guid>
      <description>Workshop planAre you new to this R business and short on time? Would you like to start working with data in R without having to go through the arduous process of learning all the programming details first? Do you have a neat data set you’d like to explore and visualise? This might be the workshop for you! Or are you an experienced old school R programmer who learned how to do everything in base R?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launch Event: Lightning Talks</title>
      <link>/post/2018/06/13/lightning-talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/06/13/lightning-talks/</guid>
      <description>We are super excited to announce that R-Ladies Sydney will launch on June 20th 2018 🎉. For our first event, we want everyone to meet someone new and learn something new so we plan to host a series of lightning talks ⚡. You are all invited to come along! We have an awesome lineup of speakers, listed below, so come along and join in!

Jessica LeeTitle: Why I R?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>